(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-03T02:00:41.506355",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
YouTube Music Weekendをご覧の皆さん、こんにちは！
Hello, everyone watching YouTube Music Weekend!
こんにちは！ / イッツ・ザ・トップ？
Hello! / Is it the top?
ウィー・アー、ReGLOSS！
We are, ReGLOSS!
ホロライブデバイスのReGLOSSです！
We are ReGLOSS from Hololive DEV_IS!
YouTube Music Weekendをご覧の方は、私たちのことをご存知ない方もいるかもしれないので
To those watching YouTube Music Weekend, since some of you might not know who we are,
一人ずつ自己紹介からいきたいと思います！
we'd like to start with self-introductions one by one!
じゃあ、奏から！ / はい！
First up, Kanade! / Yes!
ドレミファソラシド！ホロライブデバイス所属、ReGLOSSの音楽家の卵、音乃瀬奏です！
Do-Re-Mi-Fa-So-La-Ti-Do! I'm Otonose Kanade, the music student of ReGLOSS, Hololive DEV_IS!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
そして！
And next!
はい！ハッピー・ポジティブ・ジーニアス！ホロライブデバイスReGLOSSの一条莉々華だよ！みんなヤッホー！元気？
Yes! Happy, positive, genius! I'm Ichijou Ririka from Hololive DEV_IS, ReGLOSS! Hello, everyone! How are you doing?
元気だよ！
We're doing great!
そして！
And next!
はい！皆さん、こんにちは！ええ、ホロライブデバイスはReGLOSSの賑やかしネタ枠担当、儒烏風亭、もうは、全然言えてない
Yes! Hello, everyone! Um, I'm Jufutei... Wait, I'm stumbling over my words... I'm in charge of the comedy and chatter for Hololive DEV_IS, ReGLOSS,
舞茸ぐるぐるのお姉さんこと、儒烏風亭らでんでございます。どうも！
also known as the spinny Maitake big sister, Jufutei Raden. Hello!
舞茸舞茸、ぐるぐるぐるぐる！
Maitake, Maitake, spin-spin-spin-spin!
そして！
And next!
あい！ぶんぶんぶーん！ホロライブデバイスReGLOSSの、火威青！はーい、ぽんぽんちょー！
Yes! Vroom, vroom, vroom! Hiodoshi Ao of Hololive DEV_IS, ReGLOSS! Yes, "pon-pon-cho"!
イェーイ、ぽんぽんちょー！
Yeah, pon-pon-cho!
昨年に引き続き、今年もYouTube Music Weekendに参加させていただけて、とっても光栄です！
Following last year, we are incredibly honored to participate in YouTube Music Weekend again this year!
ちょっと甘噛みした。 / 何、何？噛み出さないでよ、今！可愛かった。
I stumbled a bit there. / What was that? Don't start stumbling now! It was cute, though.
今いい感じにいけるかなと思った。じゃあもう1回、もう1回やらせて！
I thought I was doing so well. Let me, let me try one more time!
昨年に引き続き、今年もYouTube Music Weekendに参加させていただけて光栄です！
Following last year, we are incredibly honored to participate in YouTube Music Weekend again this year!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
みんな、昨年は何の曲やったか覚えてる？
Everyone, do you remember which songs we performed last year?
『シンメトリー』！ / あ！『シンメトリー』やったね！
"Symmetry"! / Oh, we did "Symmetry"!
『瞬間ハートビート』はやったと思う。 / 絶対やったよ！デビュー曲だもんね。
I think we performed "Shunkan Heartbeat." / Absolutely! Since it's our debut song.
そして？
And?
そして、もう1曲やってて、当時の新曲である『うたかた歌』も披露させていただきました！
And we performed one more song! We also presented our then-new song, "Utakata Uta"!
懐かしい！
So nostalgic!
本当に懐かしいね。 / すごい、もう超昔のことのように思えるし。
It really is nostalgic. / Wow, it feels like it was such a long time ago.
当時は、こういうステージに立つわけじゃなくて。
Back then, we didn't get to stand on a stage like this.
こう、なんというか、周り…見て、これ！すごくない？
It was more like... Look at this! Isn't this amazing?
人がいっぱいいる！すごい！ありがとうございます！
There are so many people! Amazing! Thank you so much!
ちょっと、みんな嫉妬しないで。
Hey, don't get jealous, everyone.
大丈夫、画面の向こうでも今めっちゃ盛り上がってくれてると思う！
It's okay, I'm sure everyone watching through the screen is super hyped right now!
画面の向こうでも盛り上がって。
They're hyped behind the screen too.
カメラとかステージとかも、進化して再び戻ってまいりました！
With the camera and stage upgraded, we have returned once again!
イェーイ！すごい！
Yeah! Amazing!
実はですね、昨年から楽曲も増えまして、
Actually, our song library has grown since last year.
今年は3月に『サクラミライズ』、7月に『ミッドサマー・シトラス』という曲をリリースしております！
We released "Sakura Mirage" in March and "Midsummer Citrus" in July this year!
リリースしております！イェーイ！
We released them! Yeah!
また今年もこうして新しい曲をみんなに披露することができて嬉しいね！
We're so happy to be able to perform our new songs for everyone again this year!
嬉しい！嬉しい！
So happy! We are!
そしてそして！実は！
And what's more! Actually!
8月に、な、な、な、なんと！
In August, guess what!
奏たちのソロ曲を毎週連続リリースしてました！
We released our solo songs weekly back-to-back!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
らでちゃんから！
Starting with Raden-chan!
はい、らでんです！らでんのソロ曲『おとしばなし』、リリースさせていただきました。
Yes, I'm Raden! I released my solo song, "Otoshibanashi."
なんと、語りあり、言葉遊びあり、ラップありと、らでんらしさをぎゅっと詰め込んだ楽曲となっております。
It features spoken word, wordplay, and rap—a song packed tightly with everything that makes me "Raden."
そして、実は、この要素も…
And actually, this element is also...
どこかにあったりするんです。 / 気づかなかった！
in there somewhere. / I didn't notice!
あるんですね。ちょっと探して聴いてみようかな？
It really is. Let's try to find it and listen for it.
ぜひ『おとしばなし』、よろしくお願いします！
Please give "Otoshibanashi" a listen!
そして、らでんの次の週にリリースしたのは誰？
And who released theirs the week after me?
はい！奏です！
Yes! It's Kanade!
奏は『チアフル・バイブス・エコー』という…
Kanade released "Cheerful Vibes Echo"...
発音が良すぎて分からなかった。なんて言ったの？
Your pronunciation was so good I couldn't understand. What did you say?
『チアフル・バイブス・エコー』という楽曲をリリースしました！
I released a song called "Cheerful Vibes Echo"!
こちらの楽曲はですね、アコギがじゃんじゃかじゃんじゃかする感じの曲で、
This song features a lively acoustic guitar strumming along,
なんかすごく、しっとりとした曲で、朝とかに起きて聴くと
and it has a very soothing vibe. If you listen to it when you wake up in the morning,
「あ、今日もいい朝だな。頑張ろう！」ってなる曲をですね、
it makes you feel like, "Ah, what a great morning. Let's do our best today!"
作らせていただきまして。奏もすごいニコニコしながら歌ったので、元気になる、そういう楽曲になっています！
That's the kind of song we made. I sang it with a big smile on my face, so it's a song that will cheer you up!
よかったら聴いてね！
Please give it a listen!
そして、奏の次は誰だ？
And who's next after me?
はーい！莉々華の楽曲！
Yes! Ririka's song!
タイトルが『ハピネス・フェノメノン』！
The title is "Happiness Phenomenon"!
もう、いい女が全身から溢れ出ちゃうような、そんな楽曲になっていて、
It's a song that just oozes "fine woman" from head to toe,
聴くだけで気分アゲアゲ、自己肯定感アゲアゲな楽曲となってます！
so just listening to it boosts your mood and self-esteem!
朝とかお昼とか、これから頑張るぞ！って時とかに聴いてね。一緒に元気を出してもらえたらいいなと思っております！たくさん聴いてね！
Listen to it in the morning, afternoon, or whenever you're ready to tackle something! I hope it brings you energy. Please listen to it a lot!
聞いてくださいねー！
Listen to it, okay!
そして！
And next!
続いては、莉々華のソロ曲「Billi-Dally-Lilla」でした！
was Ririka's solo song, "Billi-Dally-Lilla"!
言えてない！
You bit your tongue!
ビリーダリーリラ！
Billi-Dally-Lilla! / Billi-Dally-Lilla!
っていう曲なんですけど、あの、すごいダンスナンバーで、
It's a really cool dance track...
こう、ドゥンドゥンって、こう、重低音がドゥンドゥン鳴ってて、
with a heavy bass going thud-thud like this.
なんかこう、サビに、音数はちょっと少ないんだけど、
The chorus is minimalist with fewer sounds,
静かな静寂の中に、こう、はっ、はっ、はって、乗ってく感じの、
but you groove to the beats in the silence, like "ah, ah, ah."
莉々華、結構普段ダウナーなんですけど、
I'm usually pretty chill and mellow,
その、夜のちょっとダウナーな、静かな感じと、
so it combines that slightly quiet nighttime vibe...
その重低音のグワングワンっていうかっこよさが合わさった曲になってて。
with the cool, heavy bass going "grrr-grrr."
なんか、そう、ちょっと、夜にちょっと、はぁ、って...
It's like, at night when you just want to go, "Sigh..."
聴きたい！
I want to hear it!
一人で聴いてほしい。ラップとか、ダンスブレイクもあって、
I want you to listen to it alone. It has rap and a dance break,
あの、すごいカッコいい曲になってるので、ぜひ聴いてください！
making it a really cool song, so please give it a listen!
聴いてください！
Please listen to it!
これね、実はあれなんだよね。ソロ曲、それぞれ時間帯が、
Actually, you see, each of our solo songs...
変わっていくんだよね。
corresponds to a different time of day!
らでんが夜明け前の曲で、
Mine is a song for right before dawn,
奏が、朝！
Kanade's is for the morning,
はじめがお昼！
Hajime's is for the afternoon,
莉々華、夜！
and mine is for the night!
そう。だからね、ぜひ、この順に聴くとね、ちょっとさらに深みが増すんじゃないかなーなんて思っております。
Right. So if you listen to them in this order, I think it'll make them even more immersive!
まぁ、という感じでね、それぞれReGLOSSのみんなの個性がたっぷり詰まった楽曲になっているので、
And just like that, these songs are packed with each ReGLOSS member's unique personality.
気になっていただけたら、なんと概要欄にね、リンクが貼ってありますので、そちらもぜひ、聴いてみてください！
If you're interested, the links are in the description, so please check them out!
聴いてみてください！
Please listen to them!
まあ、でもあれ。MC長げえよって、もしかしたら今、思われてるかもしれない、そこのちゃん！
Some of you might be thinking, "This talk segment is too long!" right now.
もうちょい、あの、もうちょっとだけ喋らせてね。そのあと、すぐに歌いますんでね！
Please let us talk just a tiny bit more. We'll sing right after this!
ちょっとだけ待ってね。あとちょっとね、あとちょっとね。
Just wait a little bit longer. Just a tiny bit, okay?
いや、しかもですね、実は私たち、今年の9月で、
And what's more, actually, this September...
なんと、デビュー1周年を、
we will be celebrating our 1st debut anniversary!
迎えます！
Here's to one year!
嘘！
No way!
そうなんだよ。しかも、デビュー1周年を迎えるということは、
That's right! And since we're celebrating our 1st anniversary...
3Dの記念配信もあるということ！
it means we're also having a 3D anniversary live stream!
初めて聞いた！
I'm hearing this for the first time!
そう、9月13日（土）の20時に、3Dの記念配信があります！
Yes! On Saturday, September 13th at 8 PM, we'll have our 3D anniversary stream!
何するの？
What are we going to do?
やっぱり、歌ったり、踊ったりしちゃうんじゃない？
We'll probably be singing and dancing, right?
漫才じゃないんですか？
It's not a stand-up comedy act?
あの、番長だけが踊る...
Well, maybe only the Bancho will dance...
なんで！なんでみんなで踊って歌おうよ！
Why? Let's all sing and dance together!
だって、みんな驚いてんだよ。え？やるの？って、なんでってなってるの。
But everyone is so surprised! Like, "Wait, we're doing it?" "Why?"
漫才かなと思って...
I thought it might be comedy...
冗談は置いておきつつ、
Well, joking aside...
そう、この1年間ね、みんなにこうやって見てもらうために、たくさん練習も重ねてきたので、
Yes, we've practiced a lot over this past year to perform for you all...
さらに、デビューよりもさらにパワーアップした姿を、みんなにお見せできたらなと思っております！
so we hope to show everyone how much we've powered up since our debut!
イェーイ！
Yay!
え、ちなみにさ、この1年でさ、なんか変わったこととかある？
By the way, has anything changed for you over this past year?
うわ、変わったこと？
Oh, what changed?
何もかもが変わったけどね。
Everything has changed, really!
かね、どうですか？
Kanade, what about you?
奏の変わったのあってさ、
For me, something did change.
まぁレッスンとか、ハーフアニバーサリーの時に初めて3Dライブをやってさ、
During our half-anniversary, when we had our first 3D live,
踊りながら歌うのって大変だなってすごい思ったの。
I realized how hard it is to sing while dancing.
歌、立って歌うのだったらすごい得意なのかなって思ってたけど、
I thought I was good at singing just standing up,
いざ体を動かしながら歌うってなると、息が上がっちゃって、難しいなってなって。
but once I had to move my body while singing, I ran out of breath and struggled.
そこからさ、ボイトレとか、ダンスレッスンとかを増やしてね、
Since then, I've increased my vocal training and dance lessons...
奏は、実はかなり、発声が変わりました！
and my vocal projection has actually changed a lot!
おおー！
Oh!
すごい！最初からあんなに綺麗で、歌姫だったのに、
Amazing! You were already a great diva with a beautiful voice from the start,
よりグレードアップしたってことだよね！
but you've leveled up even more!
そう、パワーアップしたので、よかったら見比べてみたりしてみてくだい！
Yes! I've powered up, so please compare the two if you'd like!
これからも、進化するぞ！
I'll keep evolving!
おー！
Oh!
さすが。おとばしら、おとばしらじゃないや、歌姫！
As expected of the Sound Pillar... I mean, our diva!
おとばしらは、本家の方...
The Sound Pillar is from the original series...
やばいやばい。
Oh dear, oh dear.
莉々華もダンス、あの、新しいジャンルを、ちょっと、なんか、習得したいなって思ってたんだけど、
I also wanted to learn some new genres of dance,
それをね、今年、2つ、チャレンジしてて。
so I challenged myself with two of them this year.
1つは、奏も言ってたタップなんだけど、
One of them is tap dance, like Kanade mentioned,
もう1個もね、別のジャンル、初めてみたりしてて。
but I also started learning another genre for the first time.
おおー！
Oh!
そう、なんか、全然違うから、もう本当にゼロからのスタートみたいな感じなの。
Right, they're so different that it really felt like starting from scratch.
本当に？
Really?
だから、これをやってて、また、なんかこうさ、3Dライブとかで、披露できる時があったら、なんかまた進化した姿を見せられるんじゃないかなって思って。
So if there's a chance to perform it at a 3D live, I think I'll be able to show everyone an even more evolved version of myself.
楽しみ！
Can't wait!
いいね！じゃあ、2人はもう得意なことをさらにまた、グレード...
That's great! So you two have upgraded your specialties even further...
...というか、のせていくような感じで頑張ってるってことだよね。
...or rather, you're working hard to get everyone pumped up, right?
ね！
Right!
はい！りりかが、あの、ちょっと心持ちが変わったなって思ってることがあって...
Yes! I, Ririka, feel like my mindset has changed a little bit...
おおー！
Oh!
最初本当にちょっとダンスが特に苦手すぎて...
At first, I was really bad at dancing, especially...
もう、こういうライブとかみんなの前で踊るみたいな時に、緊張だったりとか不安だったりとか、いっぱいあったんだけど...
When performing or dancing in front of everyone, I had so much nervousness and anxiety...
ま、今回、ま、とある曲を、あの、踊らせていただいて、歌わせていただいたんですけど...
But this time, I got to dance and sing a certain song...
それを撮った時に、なんか不安だな、って気持ちより、
And when we recorded it, instead of feeling anxious,
一緒にやってて楽しいな、っていう気持ちの方が、なんかあった気がして...
I felt like I was having so much fun doing it together with everyone...
おおー！
Oh!
え、嬉しい！って思った。
I was like, "I'm so happy!"
素敵じゃない、奥さん！素敵よ、あなた！
Isn't that wonderful, dear? You're wonderful!
それ聞けたらこっちも嬉しいよね。
Hearing that makes us happy too, right?
やったー！よかったー！
Yay! I'm so glad!
これから、これからもいっぱい歌って踊って、レッスンも頑張っていきたいと思います！
From now on, I want to keep singing, dancing, and working hard on our lessons!
がんばろう、がんばろう、がんばろう！
Let's do our best, do our best!
らでんちゃんは？らでんさは？
How about Raden-chan? Raden-san?
うん、作詞にハマってさ、この一年で。
Yeah, I've got really into songwriting this past year.
おー、ふむふむ。
Oh, I see, I see.
で、自分でね、そう、特にラップ、なんか、やっぱね、言葉が好きなの。で、特に日本語が好きで、
And, by myself, especially rap... I really love words. Especially Japanese words.
で、それでちょっと何かやりたいな、と思って、自作のラップ書いて、自分のチャンネルに投稿したりとか。
So I wanted to do something with that, so I wrote my own raps and posted them on my channel.
ね、素敵だったよね！私たちの名前とかも入れてくれてさ。
Right, that was wonderful! You even included our names.
そうそうそう、すごく言葉に愛がいっぱい。
Yes, yes, yes, there was so much love in those words.
そう、なんかそういうね、言葉と音楽みたいなところで、なんか自分で新しいチャレンジができたかな、という一年でしたね。
Yeah, so in terms of words and music, I feel like I was able to take on new challenges this past year.
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
もうみんな、それぞれにね、成長と挑戦を重ねた一年でございましたと。
So it has been a year where everyone has experienced growth and taken on challenges in their own way.
ございました！
Indeed!
でもね、まだまだ、伸び代もあるし、成長できる部分いっぱいあると思うから、これからも頑張っていこうね！
But we still have plenty of room to grow, and there's so much more we can improve on, so let's keep working hard!
がんばろう！ダンスがんばるよ！
Let's do our best! I'll do my best at dancing!
はい、ということで、今回は、先日発表されました、私たちReGLOSSの新曲「ミッドサマー・シトラス」をこのあと披露させていただきます！
All right! So, up next, we will be performing our new song "Midsummer Citrus," which was announced the other day!
イェーイ！
Yay!
3月にリリースした「サクラミラージュ」は、春の訪れを感じられる楽曲だったと思いますが、
Our previous song, "Sakura Mirage," which was released in March, brought out the feeling of spring.
今回の「ミッドサマー・シトラス」は、タイトル通り、タイトル通り...
But this time, "Midsummer Citrus" is, just like the title says... just like the title says...
夏！
Summer!
夏！暑い！あち！あち、あち！
Summer! It's hot! Hot! Hot, hot!
今、ステージ立ってるけど、日陰とかないからね！
We're standing on the stage right now, but there's no shade at all!
もう日焼けやばいって！
The sunburn is going to be terrible!
この床絶対あったかい！あつあつあつあつ！
This floor is definitely warm! Hot, hot, hot, hot!
でも、やっぱ、こうReGLOSSが、夏と一緒に、ここに帰ってきた！っていう感じするよね！
But it really feels like ReGLOSS has returned here along with the summer!
イェーイ！
Yay!
なんか爽やかなメロディとね、ちょっとこう、強いリズムが、夏の暑さを吹き飛ばしてくれるような一曲になってます！
With its refreshing melody and a powerful rhythm, this song will blow away the summer heat!
イェーイ！ドンドン！
Yay! Bam bam!
みんな、この曲のイメージとか、レコーディングのエピソードとかある？
Does anyone have any thoughts on the song's concept or any recording episodes?
はい！
Yes!
お、何？
Oh, what is it?
やっぱ、夏だし、すごい爽やかな曲だから、明るく楽しく爽やかに！っていうのをすごいイメージしながら歌ったのを覚えてる。
Since it's summer and a very refreshing song, I remember singing with the strong image of being bright, fun, and refreshing!
お、いいね！確かにそんな感じだった！
Oh, nice! Indeed, it felt like that!
本当？
Really?
感じた、感じた！
I felt it, I felt it!
やった！
Yay!
はい、はい、はい！奏もある！
Yes, yes, yes! Kanade has one too!
おお、奏、どう？
Oh, Kanade, what is it?
この楽曲のサビに、「おどってミッドサマー」っていうフレーズがあるんだけど、
In the chorus of this song, there's a phrase that goes "Odotte Midsummer" [Dance, Midsummer],
（歌う）おどって〜みっどさま〜っていう...
and I was like, "(Sings) Odotte~ Mid~summer~"...
お、歌うまっ！
Oh, you sing so well!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ふふ、その歌うな、みたいな...
Haha, you don't need to sing though...
その、「サマー」をさ、奏、すごいリズムノリノリになるの好きだから、「おどってミッドサンバ！」って歌ってた。
For that "summer" part, since I love getting into the rhythm, I was singing it like "Odotte Mid-samba!"
サンバ！
Samba!
サンバ！？サンバになっちゃった？
Samba?! Did it turn into samba?
サンバ！ってやってたら、
When I kept doing "samba!",
ディレクターさんにね、歌をこう、やってくれるディレクターさんに、「いや、ちょっとサンバすぎるんで、ちょっと...」
the vocal director said, "Um, that's a bit too much samba, so..."
「『サマー』で歌ってくださいね」って言われた。
"please sing it as 'summer.'"
調整して歌ったのを覚えてます。
I remember adjusting it when I sang.
めっちゃいいエピソードあるじゃん！初めて聞いたよ、それ。うちらにも話したことなかったじゃん、それ。初出しじゃん！
That's a really great episode! I'm hearing that for the first time. You never even told us about that. That's a scoop!
おー、はい。ウチ、サビで好きなとこがあって...
Oh, yes. I have a favorite part in the chorus...
おお！
Oh!
あの、やっぱ、サビの、みんな好きだと思うけど、最後の、ここで...
Well, in the chorus, which I think everyone loves, at the very end, here...
あ、そこね！これ！
Ah, that part! This!
これ、これ！これ難しいの、難しい！
This, this! This is so hard, so hard!
「おどってミッドサマー」の、あの、こう、結構ギコギコって動いてる。
During "Odotte Midsummer," we move quite stiffly, creakily.
紐でギコギコ、ギコギコって。
Like being pulled by strings, creak, creak.
あ、なるほどね、ギコギコね。
Ah, I see, creaking.
これが、ダンスっ子てめっちゃ好き。
As a dancer, I really love this part.
気持ちいいもんね、ここなんか。
It feels so good, right around here.
はまる、はまる。
It locks in, it locks in.
バチッとはまるよね。
It fits perfectly, right?
え、らでんちゃんはどう？
Hey, how about you, Raden-chan?
いっぱい練習しました、聴いてください！
I practiced a lot, please listen to it!
ダンスも、歌も、とにかく大変でした、聴いてください！いっぱい聴いてください！
Both the dancing and singing were incredibly hard anyway, please listen to it a lot!
はい、じゃあね、そんな「ミッドサマー・シトラス」、このあとみんなに見てもらおうと思うけど、もう早く見てもらいたいよね！
All right, well, we're about to show you "Midsummer Citrus," but we really want everyone to see it as soon as possible, right?
うん、そうそう、そろそろMC長い、長くなっちゃったし... うちら喋りすぎた！戻ろう、戻ろう！
Yeah, yeah, our MC segment is getting a bit long now... We talked too much! Let's head back, let's head back!
どうするのかなって
I wonder what we should do...
なってる気がするよ、これ
I have a feeling that's what's happening.
じゃあ
Well then...
はい
All right.
では、皆さんにもね、一緒に楽しんでもらえればと思います
So, we hope you will enjoy it with us too.
いきますよ、うん
Here we go. Yep!
それでは
And now...
どうぞー！
Please enjoy!
ミッドサマーシトラス
[Title: Midsummer Citrus]
ジャンケンポン あっち向いてホイ
Rock, paper, scissors, look that way!
やったー！
Yay!
いらっしゃーい！
Welcome!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
灼けつくような陽射し
The scorching sunlight
水面に浮かぶスパンコール
The spangles floating on the water
燥ぐ夏色と逆光の裏側で
Behind the playful summer colors and backlight
あの日の青春を呼び起こしてる
It calls back our youth from that day
デニムの裾を捲って
Rolling up our denim cuffs
裸足で走ってる砂の上
Running barefoot on the sand
硝子の淵で回り回る
Spinning around on the edge of glass
輝く瑠璃色のビー玉
A shining lapis lazuli marble
なんだか、その笑顔と紙一重だ
Somehow, it's a paper-thin line from that smile
フィルムを覗けばノンフィクション
Peering into the film, it's non-fiction
彩りに絆されたメモリー
Memories bound by colors
リセットなんて出来ないから
Since we can't just hit reset
love yourself just as you are now
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance in the midsummer
アルゴリズムの中
Inside the algorithm
瞬息でダビングして
Dubbing in the blink of an eye
切り取って喜怒哀楽
Capturing every emotion
これがきっと愛だ
This must be love
二度と忘れないように
So we'll never forget it
le lemon lime orange
キミと一生分の想い出
A lifetime of memories with you
何気ない一日が one of a kind
A casual day becomes one of a kind
よし、自己紹介いこうじゃあ！
Okay, let's do our self-introductions!
トップバッターは青くん、どうぞ！
First up is Ao-kun, go ahead!
いぇーい！
Yay!
氷が溶けては渦巻いた
As the ice melted, it swirled
魔法の杖がわりのマドラー
A stirrer acting as a magic wand
喉の奥くすぐる炭酸
Carbonation tickling the back of my throat
香る柑橘系のフレイバー
The fragrant citrus flavor
爽やかな気流にのって
Riding on a refreshing breeze
波の還りを見守ってる beachside
Watching the waves recede by the beachside
あどけない面影に焦がれ
Longing for an innocent trace of you
微かに触れそうな指先
Fingertips that almost touch
煌めきで上塗りしてしまおう
Let's paint over it with sparkles
get ahead of what you used to be
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance in the midsummer
アルゴリズムの中
Inside the algorithm
瞬息でダビングして
Dubbing in the blink of an eye
切り取って喜怒哀楽
Capturing every emotion
これがきっと愛だ
This must be love
二度と忘れないように
So we'll never forget it
ミッドサマーシトラス
Midsummer Citrus
oh yeah
いつだって we got love!
We've always got love!
okay!
キミといるだけで
Just by being with you
feel so nice ココロはまた実り
It feels so nice, my heart flourishes again
寝起きの太陽も
Even the sun, just waking up
願ってもない燦々日和？
Predicts a brilliantly sunny day?
白飛びしてしまうほど
To the point of being washed out
眩しいのは夏のせい
It's so bright because of summer
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance in the midsummer
アルゴリズムの中
Inside the algorithm
瞬息でダビングして
Dubbing in the blink of an eye
切り取って喜怒哀楽
Capturing every emotion
これがきっと愛だ
This must be love
二度と忘れないように
So we'll never forget it
le lemon lime orange
キミと一生分の想い出
A lifetime of memories with you
何気ない一日が one of a kind
A casual day becomes one of a kind